# Oussama Bouthouri

🗣 Tunis, Tunisia 🗷 oussama@bouthouri.com 🛘 23209837 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/bouthouri 🛥 https://www.bouthouri.com

#### **SUMMARY**

I lead teams to positive outcomes combining my skills in agile management,

app architecture, user experience and product design.

I like to be involved in every part of the job from architecture to deployment and day to day hustle.

part-time manager, part-time developer I never get tired of building things and solving problems.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **VP** of Engineering **xTECH**

Aug 2019 - Present, Tunis

- +100 hours teaching skills in frontend, backend and best practices that improve overall team quality by 16%.
- Trained, mentored and supervised +10 junior developers and engineers for ongoing 5 projects.
- Revised, modularized and updated old react-native codebases to modern development standards, improving performance by +250%.
- · Completed full rebuild of existing websites to perfect 100% score using the Jamstack technology with Gatsby, Contentful and Strapi.
- · Introduced agile methodologies and best practices to software development division to enhance product definition and application customization.

# **Chief Technology Officer**

Mint IT Jun 2017 - Jul 2019, Tunis

- · Built more than 10 projects from initial research and conceptual design through testing and implementation phases.
- Decrease development and deployment time by more than 15% by creating an automation tool.
- I built products for more than 5 startups all over the world.
- · Helped building one of the top 100 start-ups that shape the Fourth Industrial Revolution "World Economic Forum".
- Established milestones for projects and prepared all team members to meet aggressive deadlines using agile and scrum methodology.

# **Chief Technology Officer**

Apr 2016 - May 2017, Tunis

- · Researched new technologies, software packages and hardware products for use in website projects such as the neuroscience headset "MindMaze", augmented and virtual reality.
- · Planned and engineered RESTful web services to manipulate dynamic datasets and 3D assets.
- Optimized 3D objects and media assets for speed and performance on the web.
- · Developed landing pages, dashboards, online applications and MMO game server using Express, Socket. IO and bash scripting.
- Designed and executed security measures such as firewalls and encryption.

#### Chief Technology Officer TechnoDom Lab

· Successfully created four innovative products

Aug 2014 - Mar 2016, Tunis

- · Coordinated with Chinese manufacturer to build IoT prototypes
- · Collaborated with the research department to create the next generation integration platform for augmented and virtual reality applications.
- · Delivered performance-driven and user-centric websites that met all business requirements.
- Designed intuitive graphical user interfaces using knowledge of responsive design to improve user experience.

#### **Chief Technology Officer**

Frexes

Aug 2013 - Jul 2014, Tunis

- · Advised senior stakeholders on correct project methodologies based on business goals and internal parameters for planned development
- · Collaborated with product owners to collect and analyze client requirements, incorporating business goals and budgetary concerns into project proposals.
- · Mentored junior team members on protocols and procedures of each station to maximize contributions.
- · Orchestrated efficient large-scale software deployments, including testing features and correcting code.
- Performed quality checks on finish products to verify compliance specifications and assign appropriate quality grades.

# **Full Stack Engineer**

Frexes

Aug 2010 - Jul 2013, Tunis

- $\cdot \textit{Collaborated with design and project developers to understand project scope and offer elegant, creative and scalable solutions.}\\$
- · Audited sampling of sites prior to release of production changes to test function.
- Designed and implemented website from initial concept, site architecture and wire frames to finished deliverable.
- · Developed and implemented SEO and AB testing strategies to improve effectiveness of marketing efforts.
- · Leveraged strong understanding of WordPress core to manipulate admin and theme components.

## **PROJECTS**

## Finch.Market - Platform for household appliances

We created an online marketplace for household appliances. With a variety of features and functionalities, Finch reduces proximities between products and users. It provides a detailed display of the electrical goods and allows a delivering system to facilitate the purchase process all In a fancy design and plenty of handy shopping options.

Key features: Real-time tracking, e-purchasing, Delivery system

Technologies used: Loopback, React, OneSignal, Axios, Stripe, AWS, DPD API

#### **Grabingo - Startup of Digitized Reward System**

Grabingo comes with a variety of functions; We provide customers with the hottest offers of their favourite stores; We draw their attention to the best deals when they're nearby, and we give the best recommendation without having to look up for it. We are an innovative combination of consumption and rewarding!

Key features: Push notifications, Insights, Professional monitoring

Technologies used: Loopback, React, OneSignal, Oauth 2, Axios, ChartistJs, Google Maps, Google Analytics

### HealUp - Startup of Medical assistant and smart reminder

A smart app that assists patients during medication-taking; it organizes their time and helps memorize their drugs prescriptions as given by doctors. It comes in handy and easy functionality that facilitates the patients therapeutic periods. customize dosage, set a reminder and scan prescription, all in one App.

Key features: Medical record input, Smart Notifications, Easy custom features

Technologies used: NodeJs, Loopback, React, Axios, react-beautiful-dnd, SweetAlert, ReactStrap, husky, GitLab CI/CD

## Jobi Bar App - Events-Outlet-Drinks...

A new platform built a whole new process for digitizing pubs and after -workspaces with a variety of features and an advanced website. Jobi App includes information from all our outlets, all our events, specials, gifts, partners and many other options...

Key features: Contacts, Event calendar, Employment platform

Technologies used: Loopback, React, OneSignal, Oauth 2, Axios, Google Analytics, Google Maps, ChartistJs

#### Calvin Klein Women - New fragrance promotional mobile application

We fashioned this app to showcase the fascinating sides of Calvin Klein fragrance. It is designed with a multiplicity of games, quizzes and entertaining videos. It encloses an advanced feature of image recognition, puzzles and comes with soft feminine colours that accentuate the composition of the product.

Key features: AR-Image recognition, Push Notication, Puzzles, Quizzes & Videos

Technologies: Loopback, React, OneSignal, AWS, TensorFlow

#### One Zest - Treasure Hunt Game

One Zest is a gamification App that is based on a treasure hunt and collecting zests; It, actually, stands for objects and treasures that are green and eco-friendly, and from which the purpose is to protect the environment and encourage sustainable development through

Key features: Geofencing / Realtime mapping / QR Code Scanning Technologies: Loopback / React / socket.io / OneSignal / Google Maps

## **CERTIFICATION AND BADGES**

Google: Mobile Web Specialist

IBM: Node.js Community Leader - Level IV (Only 4 in the world)

IBM: LoopBack Advocate - Level III (Only 4 in the world)

Amazon Web Services: AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Scrum.org: Professional Scrum Master

## **EDUCATION**

# Engineering degree in Computer Science and Multimedia

Minor in Virtual Reality • Higher Institute of Arts and Multimedia • Tunis • 2014 - 2017

## Bachelor degree in Computer Science and Multimedia

Higher Institute of Arts and Multimedia ⋅ Tunis ⋅ 2011-2014